Andromeda Akoulli

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Contact info

+44(0) 7462783118



andromeda.akoulli@gmail.com



Glasgow, UK



linked in.com/in/and romed a-akoulli



github.com/AndromedaMedi

PROFILE



Junior Software Developer with 10+ years of experience in the hospitality industry in roles that have allowed me to develop strong leadership, organization and communication skills. I recently decided to make a drastic change and pursue a different career path in order to challenge myself, build my skillset and grow as an individual. Through the years I have worked with a variety of technologies to manage scheduling(Quinyx, LST), inventory(IMS, Orderly), sales(ORACLE, DC) and staff training(Attensi). Although these apps enabled me to perform better at my job, there was definitely room for improvement to optimize user experience. What started as an interest quickly became a passion for building better apps that improve the lives of its users. This led me to study Software Development at CodeClan, where I discovered that I really enjoy the creative aspect of programming, problem solving, building useful applications and collaborating with others. Quick and keen to learn, now looking to pursue my first job within the Scottish tech ecosystem to make good use of my existing skills and experience while enabling further personal and professional development.

TECHNICAL EDUCATION

Professional Software Development Codeclan, Glasgow November 2022 - March 2023

An immersive 16-week long, hands-on intensive course involving over 800 hours of coding, individual and collaborative projects and practice of Agile methodologies.

Professional Development Award (SQF Level 8)

PROJECTS

Unread - Book Tracking App Completed in 7 days | Group Project JS | React | MongoDB | API | CSS



Unread is a book tracking app that allows multiple users to track the books they read or wish to read, using the OpenLibrary API. The web app was built utilizing React on the front end which connects to the API that communicates with NoSQL database MongoDB at the backend. As a group-project, Unread was a great opportunity to collaborate and practice Scrum methodologies.

Travel Bucket List - Travel Tracking App Completed in 7 days | Solo Project Python | Express | PSQL | HTML | CSS



Travel Bucket List is a travel tracking CRUD app that allows the user to manage the countries and cities they have visited and wish to visit, using RESTful routes, a PostgreSQL database and Python(Flask). This was my first solo project, created on week 5 of the Software development course at CodeClan.

RELEVANT SKILLS

- Front End -- JavaScript | HTML | CSS | TypeScript
- Back End -- JavaScript | Python | Java
- Frameworks/Libraries -- React | Django | Express | Spring | Flask
- Databases -- SQL | PostgreSQL | MySQL | MongoDB
- Version control -- Git | GitHub
- Design Tools -- excalidraw | Draw.io | Canva | Figma
- APIs

RISE - Budget App Completed in 14 days | Group Project Java | Spring | React | JS | TS | SQL | Rest API | CSS



RISE is a personal budgeting app that allows the user to track their expenses, create savings pots and get advice on some financial aspects. The web app was built utilizing React Express on the front end written in JS and TS, connecting to the back end written in Java, employing a Spring Boot framework, communicating with SQL database.

Agile Scrum methodologies were practiced through out the project, as well as Object Oriented analysis and design using common design patterns. Effective communication was crucial for the successful delivery of the product, particularly during the implementation of new features.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY



Starbucks Supervisor

November 2019 - Present

- As a representative of a global brand I was responsible for executing store operations while setting high standards by ensuring adherence to policies and procedures, including those for staff duties, safety, cash handling, stock management and customer service.
- Managed a team of up to eight staff members by delegating tasks, following up with staff during shift and co-ordinating roles to adapt to changing customer and store needs
- Coached and mentored my team, inspiring and nurturing their passion by instilling a culture of warmth and belonging where everyone feels welcome.
- Delivered staff training and create a positive learning environment. Aided with the implementation of Attensi, apps that use gamification to help users engage with training materials, and provided feedback to the development team for future improvements.
- Helped create a positive working environment by communicating effectively, developing positive relationships, and delivering excellent customer service

Key Housing Association Support Worker

April 2019 - October 2022

- Provide high quality person-centred support to individuals, both within their home and their community
- Provide direct practical help, advice and guidance to individuals in all areas of their lives as required
- Communicate effectively, and work positively and co-operatively with managers, other employees, workers from other agencies and members of the public

Santander

Business Banking Advisor

January 2019 - March 2019

- Provided exemplary customer service to business banking customers
- Listened to customers to identify and understand their current and future needs and providing appropriate solutions to meet those needs
- Deepened customer relationships by providing simple, seamless and efficient service whilst ensuring commercial opportunities are identified and referred
- Took ownership of and resolved complex issues

EDUCATION HISTORY

BA Hons Psychology

University of the West of Scotland 2014 - 2018

CELTA Teaching English as a Second or Foreign Language

University of Cambridge 2012 - 2013

VOLUNTEER WORK & INTERESTS

Volunteer English Tutor,

Volunteer Tutor Organization (VTO) October 2021 - August 2022

Yoga & Meditation

2013 - Present

Baking

2013 - Present

Travel (when possible)

2011 - 2020

2021 - Present

LANGUAGES

- Greek native
- Albanian native
- English proficient

